Daniel A. Pinedo

Strategic Human Resources

**** 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

SUMMARY

Daniel is a people operations strategist. Being of mixed Native Mexican and Northern European ancestry, and the son of an immigrant parent, his main interest is inclusion in the global workforce. He likes studying and measuring how diverse, inclusive workplaces increase well-being for employees, and spark innovation and intrapreneurship in firms.

His vision is for the ethical implementation of industry 4.0 in relation specifically to recruitment, talent management and people development strategy in the United States and global markets.

Having over a decade of experience in IT, management, and university teaching roles, Daniel has expertise in forming, leading, and developing cross-disciplinary teams of specialists and researchers in order to complete difficult business and technical projects.

He finds joy in facilitating growth and development in employees as a trained executive and mindfulness coach with over 15 years of practice.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

m 03/2019 - Current

Same duties as Research Associate plus ownership of project deliverable content, translation of research into business case for internal clients, and engagement with primary stakeholder managers.

- · Member of Recruitment and Selection committee which planned recruitment events and created internal selection infrastructure
- · Member of Fairness Committee which vetted projects and ensured fairness in internal selection and promotion
- PROJECT 4: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into secondary implementation stage with global alignment teams
- PROJECT 5: SME and individual interviewer for values-based assessment prototype
- PROJECT 6: SME and focus group interviewer for selection assessment design prototype
- PROJECT 7: SME and consultant for leadership model synthesis and design

Research Associate

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

11/2018 - Promotion

Organizational behavior & evaluation research specialist for Global HR / Recruitment Transformation.

- PROJECT 1: Literature review for behavioral interview theory
- PROJECT 2: SME for behavioral interview theory; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- · PROJECT 3: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

Executive Coach

Getty Leadership Institute, LeAD Labs

1 05/2019 - 08/2019

% https://gli.cgu.edu/

Primary support for three senior international museum executives during leadership training and assessment center program.

- Assisted clients in creation of development plan based on assessment center, 360°, and StrengthsFinder results
- Follow-up with each client 6-8 weeks following leadership program related to completion of specific SMART goals and creation of long-term professional development goals

RECENT EXPERIENCE

External Consultant

Undisclosed Property Management Firm

1 03/2019 - 06/2019

Organizational culture consultation for private, family-owned property management firm currently undergoing succession-related change with a portfolio of over \$1 billion in residential and commercial real-estate assets.

- · Diagnosed internal-facing stress related to values signaling from family management through executive management
- Provided business case for implementing values communications strategies with potential for increased organizational commitment and overall firm performance
- · Connected business strategy with identified cultural values for implementation in management training program

Team Lead

BCG Gamma Datathon

Invite-only case competition for BCG data analytics group among graduate students from USC Marshall, UCLA Anderson, and CGU Drucker management schools.

- Recruited ad-hoc cross-functional team of experts in the fields of artificial intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, and organizational behavior
- · Provided case formulation training, strategy, and high-level architecture for technical solution

External Consultant

ICM Partners

1 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Organizational behavior project for Top 5 creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire

Lecturer

Mount Saint Mary's University

% msmu.edu

Undergraduate contract faculty position in psychology department developing and teaching courses in Research Methods, Social Psychology, Positive Psychology, and Organizational Psychology.

- Managed increase in participation in undergraduate research colloquium of students by 300% and outside attendees by over 1000%
- Academic counseling for 15 students per semester that included tracking graduation requirements, course selection, career counseling, monitoring degree progress, and crisis counseling with 100% graduation rate

Interim Director / Manager

Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab

Academic EEG lab studying brainwave correlates of meditative states of consciousness.

- · Raised private external grant pledges of \$500,000+
- · Created training program for graduate students with four paid positions for training in running experiments with human subjects

EDUCATION

MA Psychology in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Claremont Graduate University

• Emphasis in Business Administration

GPA

3.7 / 4.0

EDUCATION

MA Clinical Psychology

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

BA

Naropa University

♀ Boulder, CO

COURSEWORK HIGHLIGHTS

Management

Accounting Corporate Finance

Organizational Behavior

Organizational Behavior Organizational Culture Organizational Theory

Statistics

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis Factor Analysis Structural Equation Modeling

Programming

R C++ Java

WORK/LIFE BALANCE

⊢ Weightlifting

Bodybuilding, Olympic and Power-lifting

[♣] M

Meditation

20+ years experience in practice and teaching

/ Ar

Painting, Drawing, Contemporary/Modern Art Lover

Books

Science Fiction, Philosophy of Science, History of Math

%

Rowing

Crew, Crossfit

Ť

HikingMy favorite places are among the redwoods or fishing